calstrs.com 2013-05-01

# Privacy - CalSTRS.com

###  CalSTRS Internet Privacy Principles 

Electronic privacy is crucial for the ongoing success of the Internet as a convenient means to provide customer service. Your personal information will be used only to conduct CalSTRS-related business. 

To complete your CalSTRS business, we may need to coordinate our efforts with other parties, such as the [State Controller’s Office](http://sco.ca.gov/index.html) or your employer or health plan. 

###  Protect Your CalSTRS Information 

CalSTRS will never ask for your personal information in an unsolicited email or other type of electronic communication. If you receive such a request: 

  * The party soliciting the information is not affiliated with CalSTRS. 
  * You may not want to respond or use any hyperlinks within the request. 
  * You should: 
    * Determine the source of the email. 
    * Determine the purposes for which your personal information will be used. 

It is possible that an unsolicited email could be an attempt to obtain your personal information for fraudulent activity. 

###  CalSTRS Internet Privacy Policy 

CalSTRS is committed to responsible information handling practices. When you access or use the CalSTRS website, you agree to the terms and conditions outlined below. 

If you do not agree to these terms, do not use this website. CalSTRS may change this Internet Privacy Policy from time to time. Your use of this website will be subject to the most current version of the policy. Check this page periodically for any policy changes. 

This policy has been developed and is maintained in accordance with the Information Practices Act of 1977 (Title 1.8 [commencing with Section 1798] of Part 4 of Division 3 of the Civil Code), and Sections 11015.5 and 11019.9 of the Government Code. 

####  Policy Terms and Conditions 

CalSTRS has a responsibility to protect its computing resources. If it believes an attempt is being made through the Internet to break into or otherwise abuse the computer systems or business information, the information in the computer logs, and other means available, will be used to determine those responsible. As part of these legal efforts, the information gathered may be shared with law enforcement agencies or other authorized entities. 

####  Policy Disclaimer 

Information on this website is provided for convenient access by members and other interested parties. CalSTRS makes every attempt to ensure the information provided is reliable; however, human or technological errors remain a possibility. CalSTRS does not guarantee and will not be held responsible for any errors or omissions, or for the use of, or results obtained from the use of the information including, but not limited to: 

  * Accuracy 
  * Completeness 
  * Timeliness 
  * Correct sequencing of information 
  * Sites hyperlinked to and from the CalSTRS website 

The privacy policies or statements of other websites linked to this website may differ. CalSTRS is not responsible for the privacy practices of those websites. 

This website uses “cookies” to collect and/or store information about users. “User” means an individual who communicates with a state agency or with an agency employee or official electronically. Information from cookies assists in the improvement of this website and customer service. Website traffic patterns or the collection of aggregate data about website use is monitored. 

The following information may be collected from the computer you’re using, through cookies: 

  * Date and time you accessed this website. 
  * Name of browser software. 
  * Type of computer being used. 
  * Name of operating system. 
  * Name of website used to link to this website, if applicable. 
  * Internet Protocol Address (IPA) and domain name. 
    * IPA is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. 
  * Web pages or services you accessed at this website. 
  * Web address you visited prior to coming to this website. 
  * Web address you visit as you leave this website. 
  * Name of any form you downloaded, if applicable. 

Personal information may be collected if you contact CalSTRS through this website. This information is used to improve this website and CalSTRS customer service, and includes: 

  * Type of inquiry 
  * Relationship to CalSTRS 
  * Social Security number 
  * Date of birth 
  * First and last name 
  * Telephone numbers 
  * Email address 
  * Physical address 
  * Best times to contact you 

####  CalSTRS Website Security 

This website and computer systems are for legal and authorized use only. Unauthorized access, attempted access, or use of this or any related State of California system is a violation of [ Section 502 of the California Penal Code](http://www.leginfo.ca.gov/cgi-bin/displaycode?section=pen&group=00001-01000&file=484-502.9) and/or applicable federal law. Violations may be subject to prosecution. Individuals using this system are subject to having their activities on the website monitored and recorded. 

If you choose to submit information while using the [ myCalSTRS](https://my.calstrs.com/MyCalSTRSWebUI/Page/CommonPage.aspx?PageName=Login) website, the information will be transmitted to CalSTRS using industry-standard encryption. CalSTRS may use the email address you provide to supplement communications with you about CalSTRS business. 

[ Government Code 11015.5.(a)(6)](http://www.leginfo.ca.gov/cgi-bin/displaycode?section=gov&group=10001-11000&file=11000-11019.10) prohibits all state agencies from distributing or selling any “electronically collected personal information”, as defined below, about users to any third party without the permission of the user. CalSTRS does not sell any electronically collected personal information. Any use of electronically collected personal information will be solely for the purpose of CalSTRS business. 

“Electronically collected personal information” means any information maintained by CalSTRS that identifies or describes an individual user, including, but not limited to: 

  * Your name 
  * Social Security number 
  * Physical description 
  * Home address 
  * Home telephone number 
  * Education 
  * Financial matters 
  * Medical or employment history 
  * Password 
  * Email address 
  * Information that reveals any network location or identity 

“Electronically collected personal information” excludes any information manually submitted to a state agency by a user, whether electronically or in written form, and information on or relating to individuals who are users in a business capacity, including, but not limited to, business owners, officers, or principals of that business. 

Any information acquired by CalSTRS is subject to the limitations set forth in the Information Practices Act of 1977 (Title 1.8 [commencing with Section 1798] of Part 4 of Division 3 of the Civil Code). Some of the information you access or submit may become public records under the [ California Public Records Act (Chapter 3.5 [commencing with Section 6250] of Division 7 of Title 1 of the Government Code)](http://www.leginfo.ca.gov/cgi-bin/displaycode?section=gov&group=06001-07000&file=6250-6270). However, electronically collected personal information is exempt from requests made pursuant to the California Public Records Act. 

CalSTRS shall discard, without reuse or distribution, any electronically collected personal information upon request by the user.
